XIUHENG LI

GitHub: @leesoohang · Email: li_xiuheng@hotmail.com

SUMMARY

Accomplished professional with over 9 years of experience in the education industry from China and the UK. Currently working in Higher Education to provide advanced technical and administrative support in the maintenance and development of student systems. Motivated and highly-organised individual with a comprehensive ability to streamline administrative processes, work to demanding deadlines, and communicate effectively with people of different cultures.

PROJECTS

- Hotel Horizon
- Team Profile Generator
- README Generator
- Weather Dashboard
- Daily Planner
- Coding Quiz

Password Generator

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Student Systems and Business Support Coordinator, The University of Manchester (12/2022 – present)

- Coordinate the delivery of teaching and learning, and student administration activities, and supervise the work of the team across the area assigned to
- Support colleagues to embed locally and University-wide a culture of excellent service provision and continuous improvement, placing the student experience at the heart of what we do, with support for a single PS team working flexibly across organisational boundaries
- Support senior colleagues in the delivery of strategic and operational management across all areas of Student Systems, Records and Data, Student Administration, Teaching and Learning, and enhancement of the student experience, including applicant experience, depending on assignment
- Coordinate the delivery of team activities for the team assigned
- Maintain and develop training materials, information, advice and guidance on student systems, records and data
- Work as part of the team to support UAT testing preparation

Admissions Assistant, The University of Manchester (10/2021 – 12/2022)

- Acting as the first point of contact for admissions enquiries from prospective students maintained accurate records of 3,500+ applicants on spreadsheets and reviewed 100+ applications daily
- Supporting the organisation and delivery of interviews (60 applicants weekly), open days and post-offer conversion events with academic staff and marketing teams
- Undertaking detailed investigations of country-specific qualifications to support admissions decisions provided personalised advice on 25+ programmes to education counsellors and agents from key markets
- Monitoring Confirmation and Clearing activities administered Clearing applications to reach recruitment targets and recorded appeals after A-Level Results Day
- Supervising Right to Study, CAS and ATAS communications with international applicants verified immigration documents, issued 800+ CAS' for September intake
- Interpreting immigration updates to student visa applicants and urgent enquirers explained policies of late arrivals, financial requirement changes, BRP collection, etc.

Senior Student Services Officer, Impact Corporate English Training (12/2019 - 7/2021)

- Trained teachers and monitored their performance in course demo presentations
- Produced weekly reports to project teams with informed decision making increased student engagement time by 2 hours per week
- Liaised with senior external stakeholders about course schedule to ensure smooth delivery under COVID-19 restrictions
- Maintained relationships with existing clients with frequent follow-ups to develop referral opportunities
- Designed curriculum for multiple class types

Exhibition and Public Engagement Administrator, China Hi-Tech Fair

(11/2020)

- Assisted in the development of exhibit areas for overseas exhibitors, with remote display, promotion and live interaction
- Represented 14 European exhibitors to 450,000+ domestic and foreign visitors, and educated on industry-specific knowledge with simplified terms – generated 20 leads for further contact
- Provided visa guidance and travel support to overseas exhibitors

Senior Student Services Officer, Web Education Group (9/2014 - 9/2018)

- Supported over 200 students a year with tailored guidance on international applications and UKVI policies
- Maintained accurate records on CRM systems managed up to 250 students at the same time
- Assisted in hiring language teachers in English-speaking countries and the production of training sessions
- Organised and coordinated monthly and special activities from engagement events of 20 to citywide events of 500
- Contributed to the production of marketing campaigns on social media channels
- Delivered outstanding student experience by proactive regular follow-ups 5-star ratings for 10 consecutive months from around 1,000 monthly reviews, retention rate above 80%
- Carried out managerial duties with the direction and support of manager responsible for an international team of 20 teachers and study advisors
- Awarded Employee of the Year

Crew Liaison Coordinator, China Cup International Regatta Organising Committee (9/2013 - 11/2013)

- Developed and distributed up-to-date communications to the teams, including travel support and visa guidance
- Liaised with crew from 35 countries and regions to confirm race schedules
- Assisted with the organisation of public visitor routes and sponsor events of 500 on race days
- Produced daily reports of race records, results and rankings of 108 teams, whilst leading a team of 14 student volunteers

Events Administrator, China Hi-Tech Fair

(11/2012)

- Acted as a key point of contact for 111 delegations from 67 countries replied up to 200 emails within 24 hours
- Supported the production and updating of documentation, events handbooks and other promotional materials from the organisers
- Produced daily statistical reports of venue activities and the effectiveness of marketing activities and business forums

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Management Consulting, University of Leeds (Pass with Merit) (2018 – 2019)

Core modules: Evidence Based Consultancy, Management Consulting: The Consulting Life Cycle, People Analytics: Strategy and Practice, Information Tools for Organisations, Research Methods and Practice for Consultants, Management Consulting: Facts, Theories and Issues.

Bachelor of Arts, English Language and Literature, Shenzhen University (GPA 3.5) (2010 – 2014)

Main modules: Comprehensive English, Interpreting, Translation, Linguistics, Lexicology.

QUALIFICATIONS & SKILLS

- Chartered Management Institute (CMI) Level 7 Diploma in Professional Consulting
- Cantonese Native
- Mandarin Chinese Native
- English Full professional proficiency
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office and basic IT packages